<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Copyright (c) 2012 by Subset Games. All rights reserved -->
<FTL>

<text name="tutorial_SHIP_INTRO_1">Your ship, the Kestrel, is the focus of the typical game view.</text>
<text name="tutorial_SHIP_INTRO_2">The circular icons at the bottom of the screen are your ship's primary systems. \n\nSystems use power from the reactor (pointed at by the arrow).</text>
<text name="tutorial_SHIP_INTRO_3">These are your ship's subsystems. \n\nUnlike systems, they do not require power from the reactor.</text>
<text name="tutorial_SHIP_INTRO_4_PC">Hover your mouse over any system icon to get more information about the system. \n\nEach system's corresponding room will light up.</text>
<text name="tutorial_SHIP_INTRO_5">The Hull Meter, Shield Level and current resources are in the top left. \n\nIf your Hull Meter is reduced to zero, your ship will explode.</text>
<text name="tutorial_POWER_SYSTEM_1">We should get going, but it looks like your engines are currently powered down. \n\nGREEN system boxes are powered. WHITE system boxes are unpowered and providing no benefit to the Kestrel!</text>
<text name="tutorial_POWER_SYSTEM_2_PC">LEFT CLICK on the engine system icon and power will transfer from your REACTOR into your ENGINES. \n\nTry to keep your vital systems fully powered. RIGHT CLICK to depower a system if you want to reroute its power!</text>
<text name="tutorial_POWER_SYSTEM_2_IPAD">DRAG UP on the engine system and power will transfer from your REACTOR into your ENGINES. \n\nTry to keep your vital systems fully powered. DRAG DOWN to depower a system if you want to reroute its power!</text>
<text name="tutorial_IPAD_TOOLTIPS_IPAD">DRAG RIGHT on a system to open its info panel (as indicated by the info arrow). \n\nThis will give you a more detailed description of its purpose and status.</text>
<text name="tutorial_DAMAGE_SYSTEM_1">Oh no! Your engine room took 2 damage! Its system icon has become red to show it is broken. \n\nYour Hull Meter has also taken 2 damage.</text>
<text name="tutorial_DAMAGE_SYSTEM_2_PC">Your crew cannot repair the ship's hull, but they can fix the engines! \n\nSelect your crewmembers using LEFT CLICK. Select multiple crew by left clicking and dragging. \n\nSelect some crew to continue.</text>
<text name="tutorial_DAMAGE_SYSTEM_2_IPAD">Your crew cannot repair the ship's hull, but they can fix the engines! \n\nSelect a crewmember by TAPPING them, or select multiple crew by DRAGGING over them. \n\nSelect some crew to continue.</text>
<text name="tutorial_DAMAGE_SYSTEM_3_PC">With crew selected, RIGHT CLICK on a room to send them there. \n\nTry sending your crewmembers to the engine room.</text>
<text name="tutorial_DAMAGE_SYSTEM_3_IPAD">With crew selected, TAP a room to send them there. \n\nTry sending your crewmembers to the engine room.</text>
<text name="tutorial_DAMAGE_SYSTEM_4">Crewmembers will automatically repair systems, fight fires, fix breaches and fight intruders in their room. \n\nFighting, low oxygen and fire will hurt the crew.</text>
<text name="tutorial_DAMAGE_SYSTEM_5">Awesome, your engines are now repaired! \n\nNotice that repaired systems will automatically try to repower themselves to their last power state.</text>
<text name="tutorial_DAMAGE_SYSTEM_5_5">Some systems can be manned by crewmembers to provide a small bonus to the system. Crewmembers will automatically man any functioning system in their room. \n\nThe silhouette above the power bars shows if the system is manned.</text>
<text name="tutorial_FIRE_IPAD_1_IPAD">Oh no! A fire has broken out in your starboard airlock! You could send your crewmembers to put it out, but let's take advantage of your airlock. \n\nTAP on your door system on the bottom right to control the ship's doors.</text>
<text name="tutorial_FIRE_IPAD_2_IPAD">TAP a door to open or close it. DRAG over doors to open (or close) multiple doors quickly. \n\nTry opening the airlock DOORS now.</text>
<text name="tutorial_FIRE_PC_1_PC">Oh no! A fire has broken out in your starboard airlock! You could send your crewmembers to put it out, but let's take advantage of your airlock. \n\nOpen one of the airlock DOORS by LEFT CLICKING on it.</text>
<text name="tutorial_FIRE_END">Opening doors allows you to drain sections of your ship of oxygen and put out fires. \n\nRooms turn pink as the oxygen drains out. Your oxygen system will slowly refill your ship once leaks are gone.</text>
<text name="tutorial_DAMAGE_SYSTEM_6">Now that your engines are fixed and the fires are out, we should FTL jump to the next location. If you don't currently have a pilot, you should probably send a crewman to the helm.</text>
<text name="tutorial_DAMAGE_SYSTEM_7_PC">Each jump consumes 1 fuel. Without fuel you will be stranded and unable to jump. Jumping also requires a crewmember in the piloting system and a powered engine system. \n\nClick on the JUMP button to continue.</text>
<text name="tutorial_DAMAGE_SYSTEM_7_IPAD">Each jump consumes 1 fuel. Without fuel you will be stranded and unable to jump. Jumping also requires a crewmember in the piloting system and a powered engine system. \n\nTap the JUMP button to continue.</text>
<text name="tutorial_STAR_MAP_1_PC">This is the beacon map. A ship marks your current location. \n\nHover your mouse over a location to get more information about it. \n\nLEFT CLICK on a connecting node to travel there now.</text>
<text name="tutorial_STAR_MAP_1_IPAD">This is the beacon map. A ship marks your current location. \n\nTAP a location to get more information about it. \n\nSelect an adjacent location and tap JUMP to travel there now.</text>
<text name="tutorial_COMBAT_0_PC">Welcome to combat! You can use SPACE BAR or MIDDLE MOUSE to pause the game at any time to strategize, give commands, or reallocate your power. \n\nTry to pause the game now.</text>
<text name="tutorial_COMBAT_0_IPAD">Welcome to combat! Tap the PAUSE BUTTON to pause the game at any time to strategize, give commands, or reallocate your power. \n\nTry to pause the game now.</text>
<text name="tutorial_COMBAT_IPAD_0_IPAD">You'll notice you're focused on one ship at a time. TAP on either ship to shift your focus and enlarge that ship. \n\nWhen you're ready, TAP your weapon system to prepare to fire!</text>
<text name="tutorial_COMBAT_1_PC">You need to power your weapon to fight. The amount of power required is pictured in the weapon box (marked below). \n\nLEFT CLICK on it to power it (a powered weapon turns WHITE). RIGHT CLICK depowers a weapon.</text>
<text name="tutorial_COMBAT_1_IPAD">You need to power your weapon to fight. The amount of power required is pictured in the weapon box. \n\nTAP on it to power it (a powered weapon turns WHITE). Tapping OFF depowers a weapon.</text>
<text name="tutorial_COMBAT_2_PC">LEFT CLICK a powered weapon to arm it, then target a room in the enemy ship by LEFT CLICKING on it. You can also use the hotkeys 1-4 to access your weapons. \n\nThe weapon will fire when ready. Make sure the game is unpaused (SPACE BAR or MIDDLE MOUSE).</text>
<text name="tutorial_COMBAT_2_IPAD">The weapon is now powered. TAP the weapon again to arm it, then target a room in the enemy ship by TAPPING on it. \n\nThe weapon will fire when ready. Make sure the game is unpaused (toggled with bottom right button).</text>
<text name="tutorial_COMBAT_3">Oh no! Your 2 shot laser cannot penetrate the pirate's level 2 shields, but luckily he can't get through your shields either. \n\n(Note: Every 2 powered bars in your shields system nets you 1 more shield.)</text>
<text name="tutorial_COMBAT_4">The Artemis was automatically equipped in an available weapon slot. Shooting it expends your missiles stock, but missiles pierce through all enemy shields. \n\nUse the missile to damage the enemy SHIELDS system and then your lasers can get through as well.</text>
<text name="tutorial_COMBAT_4_5">You'll notice as enemy systems are DAMAGED or DESTROYED, their icons turn ORANGE or RED respectively. \n\nRepeatedly attacking a RED system will do no additional damage to the system, but will still damage the enemy's HULL. Reduce their hull to zero, and they will explode.</text>
<text name="tutorial_COMBAT_4_6_PC">If you need a reminder for what each enemy system icon stands for, you can mouse over the green symbols along the bottom of the target box. \n\nChoose your targets wisely, though weapons and shields often make good choices. Now defeat the Pirate!</text>
<text name="tutorial_COMBAT_4_6_IPAD">If you need a reminder for what each enemy system icon stands for, you can TAP and HOLD your finger on the green symbols along the bottom of the target box. \n\nChoose your targets wisely, though weapons and shields often make good choices.</text>
<text name="tutorial_INVENTORY_1_PC">Weapons or drones are added to your cargo if there is no more room in their respective system. \n\nLEFT CLICK on the ship info button so we can equip your new weapon.</text>
<text name="tutorial_INVENTORY_1_IPAD">Weapons or drones are added to your cargo if there is no more room in their respective system. \n\nTAP on the ship info button so we can equip your new weapon.</text>
<text name="tutorial_INVENTORY_2_PC">This is your equipment screen. You can see more detailed information about your weapons, drones, or augments by mousing over them. \n\nClick and drag your new Halberd Beam over the Artemis to swap them out. Then hit ACCEPT.</text>
<text name="tutorial_INVENTORY_2_IPAD">This is your equipment screen. You can see more detailed information about your weapons, drones, or augments by tapping them. \n\nTap and drag your new Halberd Beam over the Artemis to swap them out. Then tap ACCEPT.</text>
<text name="tutorial_COMBAT_5">Oops, your Weapon system (max power 2) is not upgraded enough to support your new weapon (power requirement 3). \n\nOpen your ship screen back up so we can fix this.</text>
<text name="tutorial_UPGRADES_1">This is the upgrade screen. You can see detailed info about your systems and upgrade them by spending SCRAP. \n\nYou can also upgrade your REACTOR at the bottom of the menu, which is important for keeping everything fully powered.</text>
<text name="tutorial_UPGRADES_1_2_PC">LEFT CLICK on your Weapon system to upgrade it. Then click ACCEPT to close the upgrades.</text>
<text name="tutorial_UPGRADES_1_2_IPAD">TAP on your Weapon system to select it, then tap the UPGRADE button on the right to spend scrap and improve the system. \n\nTap ACCEPT to close the upgrades screen when done.</text>
<text name="tutorial_UPGRADES_2_PC">Now power your new weapon. \n\nYou might need to power down your other weapon in order to have enough power (RIGHT CLICK depowers weapons).</text>
<text name="tutorial_UPGRADES_2_IPAD">Now power your new weapon. \n\nYou might need to power down your other weapon in order to have enough power (tap OFF to depower weapons).</text>
<text name="tutorial_UPGRADES_3_PC">Final tip: You can rearrange your weapons in the weapon system toolbar by clicking and dragging. \n\nIf your weapon system is damaged, this order determines the order they are depowered (right to left).</text>
<text name="tutorial_UPGRADES_3_IPAD">Final tip: You can rearrange your weapons in the weapon system toolbar by tapping and dragging. \n\nIf your weapon system is damaged, this order determines the order they are depowered (top to bottom).</text>
<text name="tutorial_DONE_1_PC">That's it for the basics. Good luck out there. \n\nPress CONTINUE to quit this tutorial.</text>
<text name="tutorial_DONE_1_IPAD">That's it for the basics. Good luck out there. \n\nTap CONTINUE to quit this tutorial.</text>
</FTL>
